CAROLINE FAIRHURST

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



fairhurst.dev



cfairhurst@protonmail.com



848-480-5258

SKILLS

- Javascript/Node.js
- Python
- Amazon Web Services
- Generative AI
- React
- Agile methodology
- Requirements engineering
- Canvas LMS
- Event-driven architecture

EDUCATION

September, 2017 - May, 2021

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE MINOR POLITICAL SCIENCE

Stockton University

- Summa Cum Laude
- Alpha Phi Omega Service <u>Fraternity</u>
- Honors Student

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Spearheading Artificial Intelligence integration for Innovation Team
- Completed AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials
- Selected as 1 of 3 Subject Matter Experts to design and write Inclusive Learning Environment Training

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 3 years of experience designing, engineering, and debugging frontend and backend applications. Collaborated directly with the VP of Technology to migrate from a monolithic repository to a serverless microsystem backend, resulting in a 99% decrease in data latency and a 30% decrease in regressions. Currently building Artificial Intelligence services to eliminate repetitive tasks and empower admins to chat with business data in natural language.

EXPERIENCE

March, 2023 - Present

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CLOUD

Kaplan University Partners and Innovation Team

- Automated Canvas LMS user management, course creation, and analytics, eliminating the need for a part-time role.
- Spearheaded Artificial Intelligent initiatives, such as automating video transcription and upload, resulting in 30 hours saved per project.
- Engineered profile service to increase user journey security, manage relationships between users, and provide a comprehensive picture of each user.

November, 2021 - March, 2023

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CLOUD

Kaplan University Partners and Innovation Team

- 1 of 2 engineers to migrate system from a monorepo to microservice event-driven AWS architecture, decreasing data latency by 99% and decreasing regressions by 30%.
- Handled hundreds of support tickets with an average time to response of 4 hours.
- Contributed to an admin React dashboard, which centralized admissions, discounting, and user lookup.

March, 2021 - November, 2021

ASSOCIATE E-LEARNING DEVELOPER

Kaplan University Partners and Innovation Team

March, 2018 - March, 2021

PRE-COLLEGE INSTRUCTOR - SAT, ACT

Kaplan Test Prep